<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Interstellar Boats</title>
      <link>https://interstellar.boats</link>
      <description>Code, Dumb Jokes, Loose Space Themes, etc. </description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://interstellar.boats/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>Now - Summer Part 2</title>
          <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://interstellar.boats/2024/10/01/</link>
          <guid>https://interstellar.boats/2024/10/01/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Summer lasts too long here. Too hot, too warm, too third thing. But the heat has
finally begun to break and I can contemplate clearly again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating&quot;&gt;Creating&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-handwritten-notes-app&quot;&gt;A Handwritten Notes &amp;quot;App&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added handwritten notes to some pages. Click off to the side if you feel like
giving them a shot. They&#x27;ll reset on reload of the page, and there&#x27;s no other
way to erase them. I haven&#x27;t tried them on an iPad, however it does seem like
the best use case for this features.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doodle at your own risk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;desk-tinkering&quot;&gt;Desk Tinkering&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reworking the &lt;del&gt;office&lt;&#x2F;del&gt; studio. Through a messy move, I&#x27;ve come into possession
of a third monitor which I&#x27;ve been trying to fit into my desk setup. The current
approach is a vertical monitor on the left, with two horizontal monitors in the
middle, and laptop on the right&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the below attached image for a good representation, captured using
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;eli.li&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Eli&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&#x27;s &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;eli.li&#x2F;_assets&#x2F;bin&#x2F;pico-cam&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Pico cam&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; , for
that amazing dithered effect.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;width:100%; padding-left:25%; padding-top:2%;padding-bottom:2%&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;2024&#x2F;09&#x2F;setup.png&quot; alt=&quot;A very unclear picture of my setup, primarily highlighting the 3 monitors as described above. There is a fourth unexplained monitor, which is actually just blocking the lamp from directly shining on me.&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be messed with again, but it&#x27;s a fairly large change to my desk, and
was a fun bit of relaxed tinkering and re-cabling so was worth noting here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;consuming&quot;&gt;Consuming&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;A_Beautifully_Foolish_Endeavor&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;A Beautifully Foolish Endeavour&amp;quot; by Hank Green&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The narrative passed between characters was great in this context, as every
new chapter was also .&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The commentary on current events is hilarious, and the failure of many of
those advances in technology in real life is fascinating, especially compared
to the life destroying success they see in the book.
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Granted the technology now is at most aspiring for what is described in the
book, so perhaps in the future there is more to worry about)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ending was very sweet. As a software engineer, the idea of retiring to a
life living off on the side of a mountain far from society is appealing. The
impact on the world lost, but the impact from the world minimized, with a
comfortable lack of impact going forward.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;watching&quot;&gt;Watching&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Frieren&quot;&gt;Frieren: Beyond Journey&#x27;s End&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This show is &lt;em&gt;fantastic&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; an dives headfirst into that feeling of nostalgia,
and creates a vibe beyond belief. I definitely watched it before these last
few months, but managed to complete a re-watch of it as well, which is just
about the highest praise I can give a show.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Delicious_in_Dungeon&quot;&gt;Delicious in Dungeon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This show was fun, and I&#x27;ll keep watching as more seasons come out but don&#x27;t
have much to say about it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;listening&quot;&gt;Listening&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;@underscores&quot;&gt;Underscores&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There something about underscore&#x27;s music that resonates with me. The catchiest
upbeat pop, mixed with the incredibly &lt;em&gt;&#x27;I don&#x27;t want to listen to this in
public&#x27;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; lyrics create a unique vibe. Maybe I&#x27;m someone who revels in
discomfort, but their music is calling several levels of society, and putting
their stories to probably the best pop music being produced today.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;considering&quot;&gt;Considering&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pluralistic.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Pluralistic&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&#x27;s approach to analytics is fantastic, in
that there is no need. The feedback received from the articles is enough to
gauge the interest on the insights within.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, this site sees no traffic. The
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.goatcounter.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;goatcounter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has provided essentially no value
and rather than let something sit passively collecting the occasional click,
I&#x27;ve decided to remove it. It works well enough and provides any bit of info
that I could want, but if basically everything is a 0, then there&#x27;s not much
purpose to it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ll worry about how much impact the site is causing when it has any impact. For
now as far as I&#x27;m concerned I&#x27;m the only one on here. And while you
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.simonoxfphys.com&#x2F;the-wikicast&quot;&gt;dear listener&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, may not be worth
counting, you are still greatly appreciated.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
.draw {
  position: fixed;
  top: 0; left: 0; bottom: 0; right: 0;
  width: 100%;
  height: 100%;
  overflow: hidden;
  z-index: -1;
}
&lt;&#x2F;style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;canvas id=&quot;draw&quot; class=&quot;draw&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;canvas&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;draw_stats&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;&#x2F;canvas&#x2F;draw.js&quot; style=&quot;white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Now - Summer Part 1</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://interstellar.boats/2024/08/10/</link>
          <guid>https://interstellar.boats/2024/08/10/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s been two months since the last &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;2024&#x2F;06&#x2F;04&#x2F;&quot;&gt;now&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and no progress on the
&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;rocket&quot;&gt;ship&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but &lt;del&gt;plenty of progress on other projects&lt;&#x2F;del&gt;. Well maybe not on
those either. But things have been busy and good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating&quot;&gt;Creating&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much visible on the creation side. Mostly been creating an enjoyable summer
for myself. By &amp;quot;creating&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;for myself&amp;quot;, I of course mean going on a trip my
wonderful friends all put together. This was a much needed break from work, and
after &lt;i title=&quot;Not burnt out, but tired out for sure.&quot;&gt;burning myself&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; on a
large refactor, it was very energizing to come back and be straight into a lot
of something else.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, given the relatively immediate timeline of upcoming real™
work, it is unlikely &lt;em&gt;much&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; progress on side projects will happen this month.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;consuming&quot;&gt;Consuming&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;100r&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;100r.co&#x2F;site&#x2F;home.html&quot;&gt;100r&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They live on a boat and make a variety of software, that is engineered, but
seems equal parts fun and efficient. Fantastic &lt;em&gt;rabbit hole&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to dive down, with
a webring linked somewhere well worth exploring. Looking into their works have
been a fantastic continuation of my shallow dive into permacomputing. (Can&#x27;t
consider it research, I&#x27;ve only been taking inspiration rather than notes)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-maybe-man-ajr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ajrbrothers.com&quot;&gt;The Maybe Man - AJR&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best augmented reality experiences I&#x27;ve been to. That&#x27;s an overloaded
term, but their use of digital screens to enhance the live performance rivaled
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Dear_Evan_Hansen&quot;&gt;Dear Evan Hansen&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (The Musical,
haven&#x27;t seen the movie) on Broadway, and blew
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;vangoghexpo.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Van Gogh Experience&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; out of the water. I am a big fan
of their music, so would probably have enjoyed it regardless of the theatrics
and effects, but the theatrics and effects we exceptional.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;lost-terminal&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lostterminal.com&quot;&gt;Lost Terminal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve listened to one episode of this podcast per night for the last ~6 months,
and it has clearly influenced my interests in just about everything. This is a
post-collapse world in which humanity is scraping by, told through the lens of
an AI named Seth. I don&#x27;t think I could recommend it enough.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With society collapsing 50-75 years in the future due to conflict over climate
change, the &amp;quot;lessons from the past&amp;quot; feel exceptionally foreboding. The
technology feels just out of reach referencing everything from the recent jumps
in artificial intelligence technology, to increasingly common FPGA based
computers. I swear I&#x27;ve learned to appreciate how radio signals work from this
podcast more than anywhere else. Wit that said, the characters are who bring
this world to life, and with them come tons of perspectives and backgrounds. All
this while managing to keep everyone confronting issues that all feel very
human, even if some happen to be living in a computer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t know what I&#x27;ll put on before bed going forward, but I am certainly
looking forward to the next season.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;reading&quot;&gt;Reading&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;An_Absolutely_Remarkable_Thing&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;An Absolutely Remarkable Thing&amp;quot; by Hank Green&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This should be required reading before you&#x27;re allowed to post on the internet.
Not because it will make you not want to, but because it will highlight the
implications of small seeming decisions. On top of that, it is a fantastic
piece of sc-fi writing, and I&#x27;ll be reading the sequel.
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Update: Have started sequel, is &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.jenniferniven.com&#x2F;atbp-book-page&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;All the Bright Places&amp;quot; by a Jennifer Niven&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This broke me a bit. I don&#x27;t want to spoil anything so this isn&#x27;t a spoiler
filled collection of thoughts. But still, read on with caution. If you&#x27;d
rather go in blind, which is my usual approach, I recommend skipping the next
paragraph. (otherwise hover to reveal)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;border-style:dashed;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;hidden&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end is what broke me. It was foreshadowed for the whole book, but I still
wasn&#x27;t ready for it. It was everything I could think of happening in my worst
nightmares, but somehow it still surprised me in the end. Looking back it
seemed inevitable from a storytelling perspective, but every ounce of my being
wishes that the signs leading up to it were taken into account by the other
characters. This book caused that much emotion in me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was fantastic, and I appreciate that the story kept going, the world kept
happening after the climax. That&#x27;s the impact of events like that. The dual
perspectives took some getting used to, but made that end even more impactful.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;considering&quot;&gt;Considering&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are incomplete thoughts that are more fun to think out loud. Enjoy, but
keep that in mind.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenced by all that&#x27;s been consumed above and plenty more, I have a lot of
thoughts about things. It&#x27;s been a while since I&#x27;ve felt that way. It&#x27;s nice to
have an opinion on actual things again, but I&#x27;m rusty at sharing those opinions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaning more towards the design side of software in my focus, and enjoying the
artistic and creative approaches there. This isn&#x27;t necessarily UI design, but
that has played a large part as well. This has sorta gotten me out of a slump
I&#x27;d been in for the last year or so in terms of thinking about software.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be more that my opinions on general software design are beginning to
form, having now worked on project long enough for it to scale the point where
the problems make themselves visible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For personal projects at least, I&#x27;m asking myself:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What world do I want to live in?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What world do I want to create?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These could be digital video game-like worlds, or they could be ways of
interacting with computers, or ways of interacting with everything. When working
in complicated distributed systems, it feels like that network of nodes is the
world, and it&#x27;s nice when that world has some sort of cohesive approach, and a
sense of logic to the design behind it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That cohesive approach is almost necessarily impossible to apply to bottom up,
federated network, where the
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cs.unm.edu&#x2F;~ackley&#x2F;papers&#x2F;hotos-11.pdf&quot;&gt;robust&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; approach to
components interacting with each other is the only viable option. Those
individaul components need to be variable, and adjustable to work with
eachother, making each one more complicated to implement. This is good in some
contexts and bad in others.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also can&#x27;t visualize that approach on a standard architecture diagram, but a
tessellated approach to visualizing it may work better to keep that sense of
cohesion. Still thinking through what that would actually look like from a
planning and implementing side as well, as visualizing those plans.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>I don&#x27;t want to write about backpacks</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://interstellar.boats/2024/06/19/</link>
          <guid>https://interstellar.boats/2024/06/19/</guid>
          <description>&lt;style&gt;
.draw {
  position: fixed;
  top: 0;
  left: 0;
  bottom: 0;
  right: 0;
  width: 100%;
  height: 100%;
  overflow: hidden;
  z-index: -1;
}

&lt;&#x2F;style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;canvas id=&quot;draw&quot; class=&quot;draw&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;canvas&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;draw_stats&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;&#x2F;canvas&#x2F;draw.js&quot; style=&quot;white-space: pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I have a problem with bags.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to replace what is currently a school bag that has been used for ~10
years. In that time it&#x27;s held up fairly well (the one it replaced lasted 7 years
if I remember correctly) and has served it&#x27;s purpose of carrying school, note
&lt;em&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; text books, a range of laptops, as well as entirely too many groceries.
It&#x27;s time has come, but there to many options that seem &lt;code&gt;good enough&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and
deciding between them has become impossible. In an effort to solve this problem
I&#x27;ll be outlining my issues with the current bag below, to restart the search
with a more direct approach.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, this is in no way a &lt;em&gt;good&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; review of this bag due to the
limited range of my bag experience. My points of comparison are a
&lt;small&gt;small&lt;&#x2F;small&gt; collection of cheap draw-string bags, a
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.llbean.com&#x2F;llb&#x2F;shop&#x2F;83531?page=super-deluxe-book-pack&amp;amp;bc=32-305-511658&amp;amp;feat=511658-GN3&amp;amp;csp=s&amp;amp;attrValue_0=1&amp;amp;pos=1&amp;amp;imgt=41&quot;&gt;school backpack&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
as a daily bag, and finally a
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.llbean.com&#x2F;llb&#x2F;shop&#x2F;123975?page=excursion-travel-pack-45l&amp;amp;bc=50-516673-514260&amp;amp;feat=514260-GN3&amp;amp;csp=f&amp;amp;attrValue_0=46399&amp;amp;pos=1&quot;&gt;travel bag&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
The
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.llbean.com&#x2F;llb&#x2F;shop&#x2F;123975?page=excursion-travel-pack-45l&amp;amp;bc=50-516673-514260&amp;amp;feat=514260-GN3&amp;amp;csp=f&amp;amp;attrValue_0=46399&amp;amp;pos=1&quot;&gt;travel bag&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
is not necessarily being replaced, but is a point of comparison and has some
problems of its own. It will probably be explored in a future post, but briefly:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has more padding than is necessary, since it&#x27;s mostly carrying clothes.
Fitting a 16&amp;quot; MacBook is not impossible, but is a bit tight, and fitting an
additional 14&amp;quot; laptop as well is not enjoyable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hundred or so bags have also been considered through online research, as well
as some brief hands on experiences with the
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.peakdesign.com&#x2F;collections&#x2F;all-bags&#x2F;products&#x2F;everyday-backpack&quot;&gt;Peak Design Everyday Bag&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
and the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.lttstore.com&#x2F;products&#x2F;backpack&quot;&gt;LTT Backpack&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; but we&#x27;re
getting ahead of ourselves. We&#x27;ll get into problems with other bags in a future
post, but this should give an idea of the price point of bag I&#x27;m considering as
well as comparing this significantly cheaper bag against.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may result in unreasonable expectations for what a &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; bag would
provide, and there&#x27;s a good chance no existing bag solves every problem I
outline. However, it will create a
&lt;i title=&quot;Concrete which probably hasn&#x27;t dried&quot;&gt;relatively concrete&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
collection of criteria for comparison. In the scenario where no bag meets this
criteria, I will
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.todepond.com&#x2F;wikiblogarden&#x2F;better-computing&#x2F;just&#x2F;&quot;&gt;just&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; build my
own.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;bag&quot;&gt;Bag:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.llbean.com&#x2F;llb&#x2F;shop&#x2F;83531?page=super-deluxe-book-pack&amp;amp;bc=32-305-511658&amp;amp;feat=511658-GN3&amp;amp;csp=s&amp;amp;attrValue_0=1&amp;amp;pos=1&amp;amp;imgt=41&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Super Deluxe Book Pack, 41L&amp;quot; by L. L. Bean&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.llbean.com&#x2F;llb&#x2F;shop&#x2F;83531?page=super-deluxe-book-pack&amp;bc=32-305-511658&amp;feat=511658-GN3&amp;csp=s&amp;attrValue_0=1&amp;pos=1&amp;imgt=41&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;pictures&#x2F;backpack&#x2F;llbean.png&quot; alt=&quot;The LLBean backpack, in color Black&quot; &#x2F;&gt; &lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;specs&quot;&gt;Specs:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Attribute&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Value&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Note&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;&lt;&#x2F;thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Max Volume&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;41 L&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Min Volume&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;41 L&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Does not expand or compress, does flatten tolerably&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Primary Material&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;420D Ripstop Nylon&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Secondary Material&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;840D Nylon&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;This is the material that rests on the ground&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Weight&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2 lb 20 oz&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;tbody&gt;&lt;&#x2F;table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a nice enough backpack, but it has the following problems:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;too-wide&quot;&gt;Too Wide&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no good way to pack it without too much of the weight being too far
from my back. I&#x27;d rather keep the weight near my body, and ideally it would
expand upwards, rather than outwards. The majority of the organizational bits
are in the wrong spot, by being in the outermost pocket any weight in those
pockets ends up being exaggerated, and the pockets end up rarely if ever used.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;too-big&quot;&gt;Too Big&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most days two of the sections are empty, those being the two outermost pockets.
The main pocket is a bit too big as well, especially for every day use. It is
the right size for travel, and has room to pack another bag if necessary. This
makes it expandable without being expandable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;too-warm&quot;&gt;Too Warm&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no ventilation on the back of the bag. Loosening in an attempt to help
makes the bag uncomfortable when properly filled. Due to the only pressure
points being the two shoulders and the lower back, unless the bag is tightened
all the way. In doing that it brings the entirety of this pack directly up
against my back, completely cutting off all airflow. Hanging off of one shoulder
helps a bit but becomes uncomfortable quickly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;too-misc&quot;&gt;Too Misc.&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn&#x27;t compact down as much as I&#x27;d like. Would rather it be smaller and
expand upwards if expanding.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has bad waist strap (and broken, from years of dangling unused)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does not inspire confidence in a rainstorm&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organization is in all the wrong spots&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water bottle holders are kinda trash&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shoulder strap pocket is kinda useless since it can&#x27;t close&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn&#x27;t get complements from strangers&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;too-good&quot;&gt;Too... good?&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can fit a full weekends worth of travel clothes, with plenty of room to spare&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can kinda fit into the travel bag if needed&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The material cleans &lt;em&gt;very&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; well&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has a key holder, essential while traveling&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has a laptop slot that can work for 14 or 16 inch laptops, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; can fit both
when necessary&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has the roughly right amount of organization&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The material is durable and cleans very well. It&#x27;s survived several
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lostterminal.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;unnecessarily salty&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; winter roads.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn&#x27;t get complements from strangers&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed only fair to outline the alright parts of this bag, since it has
worked well for so long. It will make a nice large backup bag, and may see
continued use for larger grocery runs, but it&#x27;s time of daily use is coming to
an end. There may be some followup posts cataloging my journey in search of an
alternative bag, but again only time will tell.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a bag recommendation, that solves these problems I would love a
link. I&#x27;ve been categorizing every bag I can come across, and
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mas.to&#x2F;@ncb&quot; title=&quot;TODO: Remove if there are too many suggestions&quot;&gt;very
much open to suggestions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Find me
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mas.to&#x2F;@ncb&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@ncb@mas.to&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Now - Start the Ship</title>
          <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://interstellar.boats/2024/06/04/</link>
          <guid>https://interstellar.boats/2024/06/04/</guid>
          <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating&quot;&gt;Creating&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m building a rocket, here&#x27;s progress so far:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requires JavaScript, sorry :(&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;noscript&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;canvas id=&quot;demo_canvas&quot; class=&quot;demo_canvas&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;canvas&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;demo.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First time messing with the
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;developer.mozilla.org&#x2F;en-US&#x2F;docs&#x2F;Web&#x2F;API&#x2F;Canvas_API&quot;&gt;canvas&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and it&#x27;s
been great. Few rules, quick reloads, it&#x27;s been a nice change of pace from the
daily Rust grind. I also haven&#x27;t done much JavaScript recently so it&#x27;s been fun
to act on all the bad ideas the Rust compiler discourages, although some of
those good habits have also persisted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b class=&quot;warning&quot;&gt;Note:&lt;&#x2F;b&gt; Inspect source at your own risk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#x27;s still a bunch to do, so expect more demos eventually, as well updates
posted &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mas.to&#x2F;@ncb&quot;&gt;here on Mastodon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;consuming&quot;&gt;Consuming&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concerts!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.jacobcollier.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Jacob Collier&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fantastic concert, it was like being in a choir again for the first time in
years, played all of the best songs and was a great vibe in the crowd.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.manchild.band&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Johnny Manchild and the Poor Bastards&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of my favorite bands. Bunch of the new songs and they also played plenty
of their older ones. Didn&#x27;t tour with the full horn section, but that
would&#x27;ve been tight in the upstairs bar corner, so I understand. The opener
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;holdfast.band&#x2F;&quot;&gt;HOLDFAST&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was also fantastic, and super talented.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Play? Play!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;stereophonicplay.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Stereophonic&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was a weird experience having only previously been to musicals, but it was
funny, lighthearted, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; serious. A good time all around.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;considering&quot;&gt;Considering&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to take some &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mas.to&#x2F;@TodePond&#x2F;112512932772527968&quot;&gt;inspiration&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mas.to&#x2F;@TodePond&#x2F;112514334430759370&quot;&gt;advice&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and start actually
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mas.to&#x2F;@ncb&quot;&gt;posting on mastodon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It&#x27;ll start with the
aforementioned updates on the rocket and may evolve if I find a good rhythm.
Unfortunately I&#x27;m not interesting so the posts will probably be infrequent,
but they will &lt;em&gt;be&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#x27;t expect I&#x27;ll be insulting all 6 followers. Only 2 or 3 max.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still haven&#x27;t found a good naming scheme for these. Going to still start with
the &lt;code&gt;now&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, but hopefully have something noteworthy to include with as a title
as well, but if not the occasionaly &lt;code&gt;now&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; is fine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Now</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://interstellar.boats/2024/04/24/</link>
          <guid>https://interstellar.boats/2024/04/24/</guid>
          <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating&quot;&gt;Creating&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Torn Leaf Submission!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mas.to&#x2F;@ncb&#x2F;112261787665163204&quot;&gt;submission&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to Torn Leaf! More
details at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tornleaf.gallery&#x2F;&quot;&gt;tornleaf.gallery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as to what this is.
It was fun, haven&#x27;t had an excuse to mess around with Unreal for a while.
Ended up tinkering a ton.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking forward to more in the future, whether through prompts like this or
other sources of inspiration to create something cool&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;consuming&quot;&gt;Consuming&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Dune_(novel)&quot;&gt;Dune&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by Frank Herbert.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was very good. Looking forward to watching the movies. Having now read the
books I can see why the first movie wasn&#x27;t talked about much.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think the world building going on in the first part will be fascinating to
see. The story that follows as result of that world was fantastically executed
in the novel, and there are some scenes that I could see lending themselves
well to the screen.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did not finish
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Nightfall_and_Other_Stories&quot;&gt;Nightfall and Other Stories&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
by Isaac Asimov.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished roughly half of the stories. Nightfall was well worth the read before
the eclipse. Will check out from library again in the future.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=aYT2se94eU0&amp;amp;list=WL&quot;&gt;The Computer Revolution Revolution Hasn&#x27;t Happened Yet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spurred on by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;futureofcoding.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the Future of coding home page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, I
watched this talk. Dozens of the core ideas and issues of software and
architecture design are outlined here. It felt refreshing, and a bit
concerning to hear the same ideas still be relevant. The different scales of
operation have only made the solutions to the same problems different as well,
it hasn&#x27;t solved them. I suppose that&#x27;s job security if nothing else.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;considering&quot;&gt;Considering&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was taking a look at some of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;macwright.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tom MacWright&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&#x27;s posts,
specifically &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;macwright.com&#x2F;2019&#x2F;02&#x2F;06&#x2F;how-to-blog&quot;&gt;this one&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and the
reasoning about posting on a schedule clarified some things for me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;now&quot;&gt;Now&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was already inspired by the
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;macwright.com&#x2F;2024&#x2F;04&#x2F;02&#x2F;recently&quot;&gt;recently&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; posts. I understood that
it would help with writing more, and had seen the benefits of that at my first
internship, but I missed the second point entirely. Having this as a single
separate page leaves the website looking a bit empty, despite the &lt;em&gt;relatively&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
consistent updates. As such these are being reworked into &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; posts, to
make it clear that the website isn&#x27;t abandoned.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It does look goofy with the names all listed as &amp;quot;now&amp;quot;, so I&#x27;ll probalby rename
them in the future. Really this should be further encouragement to write more
of those posts.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Now</title>
          <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://interstellar.boats/2024/02/27/</link>
          <guid>https://interstellar.boats/2024/02/27/</guid>
          <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating&quot;&gt;Creating&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on some spotify data analysis based on the existing
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;Yooooomi&#x2F;your_spotify&quot;&gt;your_spotify&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; tool.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally that will handle the tracking, since it can also import history.
Then we will can use their api for our own fun.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hold up on this is spotify&#x27;s lifetime data export, which can take up to
30 days. No rush though on this so it&#x27;s alright.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prototyping a game. Well, more trying to use Unreal Engine to test mechanics,
may move to Godot or Bevy in the future if Unreal ends up being too heavy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music, mostly tinkering with stuff though, nothing for the world to hear any
time soon.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;consuming&quot;&gt;Consuming&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Nightfall_and_Other_Stories&quot;&gt;Nightfall and Other Stories&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
by Isaac Asimov
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each of these has been a thinker to some extent or another, only about half
way through so far.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asimov&#x27;s preamble about the atomic bomb&#x27;s effect in science fiction writing
was fascinating. It&#x27;s when when the lines began blurring between the distant
future and &amp;quot;tomorrow&amp;quot; for him and many other writers. A middle ground may be
impossible, as eventually that length of time or amount of progress passes
and what was once science fiction becomes either an impossibility or a fact
of life.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played some Games:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;reflexarena.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Reflex Arena&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Haven&#x27;t played a Quake-like game in forever. Terrible at them but they&#x27;re
ridiculous and fun, regardless of skill.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tetr.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;tetr.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An online competitive Tetris, which was more heated than Reflex Arena.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;raft-game.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Raft&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joined a few friends late on this. Much more calm. One &amp;quot;level&amp;quot; explored
simultaneously a fear of heights and of depths. May be reading into it too
much, but intentional or not it was fantastic. Can&#x27;t speak to the rest of
the game as there is a lot of early game left to explore.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;considering&quot;&gt;Considering&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing to note. Head&#x27;s been empty and anything outside work has been a
struggle. Other than the noodling above, there hasn&#x27;t been much real progress
on projects.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video games as an escape has been fairly nice, especially while its still too
cold to enjoy exercise alone most days after work.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the depths of covid, going for bike rides after work was great.
Getting those started now is a bit more difficult though. Trails around here
also don&#x27;t have as nice of a destination.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Now</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://interstellar.boats/2024/02/04/</link>
          <guid>https://interstellar.boats/2024/02/04/</guid>
          <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating&quot;&gt;Creating&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;nxb9626&#x2F;.config&#x2F;tree&#x2F;7c6bd38ff6b7c8ed9d201ae28d0cdb4c7a1cba81&#x2F;zed&quot;&gt;Zed configurations&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, now picking Zed from the top of the list when opening an editor. Most
stuff is a still bit easier in VS Code still, some is better done in
terminal through vim&#x2F;nvim&#x2F;helix. Unsurprisingly, Zed has been great for
working on Rust code so far.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug with the the site&#x27;s color choices, so highlights should now
actually work for everyone as expected, as well as some other oddities about
the site&#x27;s css.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;consuming&quot;&gt;Consuming&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;@JohnnyManchild&quot;&gt;Johnny Manchild and the Poor Bastards&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=7ua-pQ7Gqo8&quot;&gt;We&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has been at the top of my
On Repeat for a few weeks recently, and their new singles
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=3no4iiUzdww&quot;&gt;Oh, Songbird&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=xDKSbsgbqFI&quot;&gt;Fake Me Out&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are both
rocketing upwards on that list as well.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their music made up 25% of my top 100 songs from 2020, and they have
maintained control of a portion of that list every year since, so can not
recommend them enough.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;@CaravanPalace&quot;&gt;Caravan Palace&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has been the other coding background music of choice, and is popular but
still worth recommending for some electro swing fun.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=GEENb-BmmJ0&quot;&gt;Leena&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from their Chronologic
album is a gem (based on the spotify plays), as is
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=9Lq6KSPcdiY&quot;&gt;April&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but the whole album is
worth a listen.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple Vision Pro coverage. Seems neat. Looking forward to a consumer version
in the future and noting down any good app ideas for future side projects.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;considering&quot;&gt;Considering&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;linear.app&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Linear.app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is pretty nice, but will need to continue
testing before it fully replaces my (imperfect) Post-it note system.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting hooked on the keyboard shortcuts seems like a slippery slope to
being stuck with the good and bad of this tool, there&#x27;s no other with such
easy to learn shortcuts. (If you know of one please reach out!)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May be possible to do all of this in Obsidian, but having dedicated tools
for dedicated tasks is occasionally helpful.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Now</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://interstellar.boats/2024/01/28/</link>
          <guid>https://interstellar.boats/2024/01/28/</guid>
          <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating&quot;&gt;Creating&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made an old project public &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;IvsjULPtDCw&quot;&gt;on the tube&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The few comments of feedback have been amazing. Not &lt;em&gt;always&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; intentionally
constructive, but all feed back can be made constructive.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On that note, rendering&#x2F;game engines are currently interesting.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deciding where to focus is difficult, Unreal Engine and Bevy are the current
wildly different choices, so deciding to focus on one necessarily means not
focusing much on the other.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This blog continues to evolve.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;consuming&quot;&gt;Consuming&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Turtles_All_the_Way_Down_(novel)&quot;&gt;Turtles All the Way Down&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
by John Green
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;So far:&lt;&#x2F;del&gt; Great, difficult to read on a train without missing my stop.
Need to schedule reading time outside of public transport for it.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit: &lt;em&gt;Rather than schedule time, I read the last half of the book the day
after this update. I maintain that it is a fantastic book, and can easily
recommend it.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Very&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; different from the
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Foundation_series&quot;&gt;Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; series by
Isaac Asmiov which I finished late last year, and was excellent .&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entirely too much minimalism &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;tube&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inevitable in times of turbulent travel. Packing up life into a bag is a
fascinating challenge.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probably too much of the rest of the tube as well.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Nightfall_and_Other_Stories&quot;&gt;Nightfall and Other Stories&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
by Isaac Asimov
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is on deck, and given that it was checked out from the library it has
given all active books a deadline.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;considering&quot;&gt;Considering&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Giving up&amp;quot; on VS Code
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;neovim.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Neovim&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is probably enough for code editing at this
point.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zed.dev&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Zed&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; exists as an alluring alternative as well&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local git management is primarily where my flow could use some work for both
of the above, maybe a search for a
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;git-scm.com&#x2F;downloads&#x2F;guis&quot;&gt;dedicated git app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; should be underway.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to post more often
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A whole post seems annoying to do for each of these though. So now we have
the &lt;code&gt;now&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; page, inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;j3s.sh&#x2F;now.html&quot;&gt;j3s.sh&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;taylor.town&#x2F;now&quot;&gt;taylor.town&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;macwright.com&#x2F;now&quot;&gt;tommacwright.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. All of whom have been added
to &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;~&quot;&gt;~&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This format of &lt;code&gt;now&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; is loosely derived from my first internship&#x27;s daily
log, so shout out to Drew and Heather for starting me on that, and the rest
of the team there for enjoying my rambles.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Stop the Music.app</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://interstellar.boats/music.app/</link>
          <guid>https://interstellar.boats/music.app/</guid>
          <description>&lt;style&gt;

.spotify&gt;a:hover {
  color: hsl(141, 73%, 42%);
}

.obsidian&gt;a:hover {
  color: hsl(256, 100%, 67%);
}

.shortery&gt;p&gt;img {
  border-radius: unset;
  box-shadow: unset;
  width: 90%;
  padding-left: 5%;
  padding-right: 5%;
}

.hot-corner&gt;p {
  width: 100%;
  padding-left: 30%;
  padding-top: 5%;
  padding-bottom: 5%;
  padding-right: 30%;
}

.hot-corner&gt;p&gt;img {
  width: 40%;
  box-shadow: -5px 5px 30px 6px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.45);
  background-color: brgba(0, 0, 0, 0.45);
  border-radius: 3%;
}

&lt;&#x2F;style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple does not provide an option to rebind
&lt;i class=&quot;unset&quot; title=&quot;Also referred to as the button located on the F8 key, may require the fn key to be pressed in order to activate.&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;⏯&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;,
also known as the
&lt;i class=&quot;unset&quot; title=&quot;Also referred to as the button located on the F8 key, may require the fn key to be pressed in order to activate.&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Play&#x2F;Pause&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;
button&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;. By default it opens
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;support.apple.com&#x2F;guide&#x2F;music&#x2F;welcome&#x2F;mac&quot;&gt;Music.app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; when nothing is
playing, whereas I would prefer that it open
&lt;i class=&quot;spotify unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;open.spotify.com&#x2F;?&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; and resume
playback&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;tombonez&#x2F;noTunes&quot;&gt;noTunes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; exists as a dedicated app to
solve this problem. Unfortunately it did not work for me. It &lt;em&gt;did&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; block
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;support.apple.com&#x2F;guide&#x2F;music&#x2F;welcome&#x2F;mac&quot;&gt;Music.app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from opening but
there was an issue around launching and starting
&lt;i class=&quot;spotify unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;open.spotify.com&#x2F;?&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is probably possible for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;tombonez&#x2F;noTunes&quot;&gt;noTunes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to
perform perfectly, however I searched on for a
&lt;i class=&quot;unset&quot; title=&quot;I want this to actually solve all of my life&#x27;s problems, not just the music app.&quot;&gt;
more general solution instead.&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
(&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;support.apple.com&#x2F;guide&#x2F;music&#x2F;welcome&#x2F;mac&quot;&gt;Music.app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is not the only
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;interstellar.boats&#x2F;music.app&#x2F;#the-notes-app&quot;&gt;default app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; I would rather not use&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) If this or another
solution&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2&quot;&gt;2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt; works for you:
&lt;i class=&quot;unset&quot; title=&quot;This is genuine.&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Great!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;. Operating
correctly&lt;i class=&quot;unset&quot; title=&quot;Peter&#x27;s Comma Correction Suggestion&quot;&gt;,&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; it
almost certainly would be a smoother experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-fix&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;interstellar.boats&#x2F;music.app&#x2F;#the-fix&quot;&gt;The Fix&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;i class=&quot;unset&quot; title=&quot;forever finding fun in forming phrases...&quot;&gt;forage
for a finer fix followed another flow, and for a patchwork solution the final
result functions fairly well&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;. It pairs Apple&#x27;s
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.apple.com&#x2F;us&#x2F;app&#x2F;shortcuts&#x2F;id915249335&quot;&gt;Shortcuts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which handles
the applications, with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.lgerckens.de&#x2F;shortery&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Shortery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as a
trigger, and is completed by running a small
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;developer.apple.com&#x2F;library&#x2F;archive&#x2F;documentation&#x2F;AppleScript&#x2F;Conceptual&#x2F;AppleScriptLangGuide&#x2F;introduction&#x2F;ASLR_intro.html&quot;&gt;AppleScript&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
to start the music.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; we need
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.icloud.com&#x2F;shortcuts&#x2F;113f5fa3b9be4e2da5c20481f5fac045&quot;&gt;the shortcut&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.icloud.com&#x2F;shortcuts&#x2F;113f5fa3b9be4e2da5c20481f5fac045&quot;&gt;Here the shortcut is shared through iCloud, and includes the few lines of necessary AppleScript.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch and Focus
&lt;i class=&quot;spotify unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;open.spotify.com&#x2F;?&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the few lines of
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;developer.apple.com&#x2F;library&#x2F;archive&#x2F;documentation&#x2F;AppleScript&#x2F;Conceptual&#x2F;AppleScriptLangGuide&#x2F;introduction&#x2F;ASLR_intro.html&quot;&gt;AppleScript&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
which send a
&lt;i class=&quot;unset&quot; title=&quot;I trust you know to know what this key is.&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Space Bar&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
key press to
&lt;i class=&quot;spotify unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;open.spotify.com&#x2F;?&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide and Quit &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;support.apple.com&#x2F;guide&#x2F;music&#x2F;welcome&#x2F;mac&quot;&gt;Music.app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may look a bit out of order, but the time it takes for
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;support.apple.com&#x2F;guide&#x2F;music&#x2F;welcome&#x2F;mac&quot;&gt;Music.app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to launch is
better spent starting
&lt;i class=&quot;spotify unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;open.spotify.com&#x2F;?&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; and beginning
playback. Cleanup can occur hidden in the background.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; step is to setup &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.lgerckens.de&#x2F;shortery&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Shortery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;i class=&quot;shortery&quot; &gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;pictures&#x2F;musicapp&#x2F;shortery.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Shortery as it should configured to run on launch of an application&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
Here &lt;u&gt;⊕ Add Shortcut Trigger&lt;&#x2F;u&gt; and select:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;Application&lt;&#x2F;u&gt; as the trigger type&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our &lt;u&gt;No Music&lt;&#x2F;u&gt; shortcut.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;support.apple.com&#x2F;guide&#x2F;music&#x2F;welcome&#x2F;mac&quot;&gt;Music.app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;u&gt; as the
Application&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This only runs when the music app launches, keeping our shortcut simple and
allowing all other default behavior of
&lt;i class=&quot;unset&quot; title=&quot;Also known as the Play&#x2F;Pause button, which shares a key with F8, so may require fn.&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;⏯&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
can remain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to &lt;u&gt;Allow Running Scripts&lt;&#x2F;u&gt; in
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.apple.com&#x2F;us&#x2F;app&#x2F;shortcuts&#x2F;id915249335&quot;&gt;Shortcuts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; under
&lt;code&gt;Settings... &amp;gt; Advanced&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will &lt;em&gt;also&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; need to click accept on a few automation and accessibility
access alerts, needed to send the key press, and watch for application
launches.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-instances-of-music-app&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;interstellar.boats&#x2F;music.app&#x2F;#other-instances-of-music-app&quot;&gt;Other Instances of Music.app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above automation solves the primary keyboard issue at hand, however it still
launches as the default player for any audio files. This &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;will&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; be annoying
as with this shortcut setup the music app will quit every time it opens.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily Apple has allowed the ability to adjust this to
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.videolan.org&#x2F;vlc&#x2F;&quot;&gt;another app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obvious flow in finder (&lt;code&gt;Open with &amp;gt; Other... &amp;gt; VLC&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;) does not provide the
option to change the default for &lt;strong&gt;all files&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; of that type. This only opens
that specific file in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.videolan.org&#x2F;vlc&#x2F;&quot;&gt;VLC&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apple.stackexchange.com&#x2F;questions&#x2F;182871&#x2F;i-want-to-make-vlc-my-default-player-on-mac-os-x-10-10-3&quot;&gt;however as described here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
the less obvious flow can be used:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Right Click &amp;gt; Get Info &amp;gt; Open With: VLC &amp;gt; Change All...&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This must be done for each file &lt;strong&gt;type&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; but &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; we will run out of new
file types to update, and this will not be an issue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-notes-app&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;interstellar.boats&#x2F;music.app&#x2F;#the-notes-app&quot;&gt;The Notes.app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote this post in
&lt;i class=&quot;obsidian unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;obsidian.md&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;; which is where I
handle all of my notes. I do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; use the included
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;support.apple.com&#x2F;guide&#x2F;notes&#x2F;welcome&#x2F;mac&quot;&gt;Notes.app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but do like the
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;support.apple.com&#x2F;guide&#x2F;mac-help&#x2F;use-hot-corners-mchlp3000&#x2F;mac&quot;&gt;Hot Corner Shortcut&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
that exists for it. It would be more useful if it could launch
&lt;i class=&quot;obsidian unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;obsidian.md&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;. Unfortunately
that shortcut is limited to only a few actions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;i class=&quot;hot-corner&quot; &gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;pictures&#x2F;musicapp&#x2F;hot_corner_shortcut.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of the (rather limited) Hot Corner Shortcut options&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;support.apple.com&#x2F;guide&#x2F;notes&#x2F;welcome&#x2F;mac&quot;&gt;Notes.app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will launch from
the &lt;code&gt;Quick Note&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; action so we can follow a familiar pattern and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;interstellar.boats&#x2F;music.app&#x2F;#the-fix&quot;&gt;fix&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
that right up. Swapping to sending &lt;code&gt;Ctrl + n&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; could finalize this shortcut for a
quick note, but &lt;i class=&quot;obsidian unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;obsidian.md&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
has &lt;i class=&quot;obsidian unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;help.obsidian.md&#x2F;Home&quot;&gt;options&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; and
&lt;i class=&quot;obsidian unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;obsidian.md&#x2F;plugins&quot;&gt;plugins&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; for daily
notes so this all will be left left as an exercise for the reader.&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#3&quot;&gt;3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! A footnote for the first paragraph! Generally I end up clicking
&lt;i class=&quot;unset&quot; title=&quot;Also known as the Play&#x2F;Pause button, which shares a key with F8, so may require fn.&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;⏯&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
under the assumption
&lt;i class=&quot;spotify unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;open.spotify.com&#x2F;?&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; is
already open since in my it lives in desktop view to the right, so I am
expecting playback to begin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;2&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Options such as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;karabiner-elements.pqrs.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Karabiner Elements&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.keyboardmaestro.com&#x2F;main&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Keyboard Maestro&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; also exist and
may provide a solution to modifying this operation closer to the keyboard
level, but have not been thoroughly explored, and are left as an exercise to
the reader.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;3&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;spotify unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;open.spotify.com&#x2F;?&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; and &lt;i class=&quot;obsidian unset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;obsidian.md&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; are used in
this write up, however the shortcut should accommodate swapping to whichever
apps you like, as well the
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;developer.apple.com&#x2F;library&#x2F;archive&#x2F;documentation&#x2F;AppleScript&#x2F;Conceptual&#x2F;AppleScriptLangGuide&#x2F;introduction&#x2F;ASLR_intro.html&quot;&gt;AppleScript&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
swapping the keys pressed,
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apple.stackexchange.com&#x2F;questions&#x2F;36943&#x2F;how-do-i-automate-a-key-press-in-applescript&quot;&gt;with more details here on that front&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Maintenance Log</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://interstellar.boats/2023/9/</link>
          <guid>https://interstellar.boats/2023/9/</guid>
          <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-site-has-launched-rocket&quot;&gt;The site has launched! 🚀&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously the site was not launched, this is the primary change you may have noticed this month. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been a few tweaks since launch earlier this month.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Descriptions now show up correctly on the main posts page. The mobile display for these is still a work in progress.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The colors have been adjusted to better fit contrast level guidelines, which were notably a bit low in the original light mode. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sunk-ships&quot;&gt;Sunk ships&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the site&#x27;s changes, there has been work on a few posts, however nothing is  complete enough to be published. Of these, only one has been canned:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An analysis of the mythical labs portrayed in Apple&#x27;s recent demos.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranging from stationary bike and lab stool choice to a 1984 Macintosh in the background to determining which devices went with which developer boards, there was plenty of distraction from the products being presented. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone has gone through and discussed these facets of the presentation I would love to hear about it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Lift Off!</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://interstellar.boats/hello/</link>
          <guid>https://interstellar.boats/hello/</guid>
          <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;hello&quot;&gt;Hello!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting off on our maiden voyage, we dive deep into the vast speckled void.
Goodbye to the unknown, hello to the
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Observable_universe&quot;&gt;unobservable&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;rss.xml&quot;&gt;Modify your orbit to return&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, or breach celestial escape velocity and
venture forth, the universe is &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;random&quot;&gt;yours to explore&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
